Guide to the Edith Gombos Papers, 1960-1979
Department of Special Collections
Gombos, Edith. Papers,
1960-1979
M1175
Gombos, Edith
.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Includes an unpublished rough and corrected draft manuscript by Jean-Paul Sartre (29 pp), messages from both Sartre and Simone de Beauvoir, de Beauvoir letters (5), Henry Miller letters and cards (16), Graham Greene letters (28), and 11 taped interviews with Sartre, Ingmar Bergman, Lawrence Durrell, Graham Greene, James Baldwin, Amos Oz, Julio Cortazar, Woody Allen, Henry Miller, and Isaac Bashevis Singer.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access unrestricted, except for the original cassette tapes, which will be preserved as archival copies. Use copies will be made as soon as possible.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 2000.
Biography
Edith Gombos [Edith Sorel, pseudonym] was a journalist for the Cuban paper REVOLUTION, ca. 1960, and thereafter a free-lance interviewer of international status, her work published in several languages. Her career began with her introduction of de Beauvoir to Cuba, and did not conclude until the mid-1990s. Through the agency of Henry Miller she had a story published in English.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
Includes an unpublished rough and corrected draft manuscript by Jean-Paul Sartre (29 pp), messages from both Sartre and Simone de Beauvoir, de Beauvoir letters (5), Henry Miller letters and cards (16), Graham Greene letters (28), and 11 taped interviews with Sartre, Ingmar Bergman, Lawrence Durrell, Graham Greene, James Baldwin, Amos Oz, Julio Cortazar, Woody Allen, Henry Miller, and Isaac Bashevis Singer.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Allen, Woody, 1935-; Baldwin, James, 1924-; Beauvoir, Simone de. 1908-; Bergman, Ingmar, 1918-; Cortâazar, Julio.; Durrell, Lawrence.; Greene, Graham, 1904-; Miller, Henry, 1891-; Oz, Amos.; Sartre, Jean-Paul, 1905-; Singer, Isaac Bashevis, 1904-; Sorel, Edith, pseud.; American literature--20th century.; French literature--20th century.; Cuba--History--Revolution, 1959.; Cuba--Intellectual life.; Phonotapes.
Collection Contents
- Jean-Paul Sartre. "Idéologie et revolution"1960, original manuscript of an essay, 29 pp, received from the author, in Havana (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Jean-Paul Sartre. Handwritten messages on the occasion of the anniversary of the Cuban revolution received in Paris1960, 2 leaves (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Simone de Beauvoir. Handwritten messages on the occasion of the Cuban revolution, written on the back of a personal note addressed to Mme. Sorel, Paris1960, 2 leaves (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Simone de Beauvoir. Five letters to Mme. Sorel, Paris1960 - 1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Henry Miller. Twelve letters and four postcards, written to Mme. Sorel from Pacific Palisades, California1978 - 1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Graham Greene. Twenty-eight letters to Mme. Sorel, written from Paris and Antibes1966 - 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Conversation with Jean-Paul Sartre, Paris (120 min., in French)1976 Sept. 15, Audio cassette (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Conversation with Ingmar Bergman, at the Residenz Theater of Munich (90 mins., in English)1977 Mar. 13, Audio cassette (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Conversation with Lawrence Durrell, at Sommière (France) (90 min., in French and English)1977 May 21, Audio cassette (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Conversation with Graham Greene, at Antibes (France)1977 June 15, (120 mins., in English) Audio cassette (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Conversation with James Baldwin, in Saint-Paul de Vence (France) 1977 July 14, (45 mins., in English) Audio cassette (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Conversation with Amos Oz, at Kibbutz Hulda (Israel) 1977 Jan. 7, (45 mins., in English) Audio cassette (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Conversation with Julio Cortazar, in Paris1977 Sept 6, (30 mins., in French) Audio cassette (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Conversation with Woody Allen, in New York1977 Nov. 16, (35 mins., in English) Audio cassette (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Conversation with Henry Miller, at Pacific Palisades, Calif.1977 Dec. 8, (90 mins., in English) Audio cassette (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Conversation with Henry Miller, at Pacific Palisades, Calif.1978 Sept 19, (90 mins., in English) Audio cassette (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Conversation with Henry Miller, at Pacific Palisades, Calif.1978 Sept 19, (90 mins., in English) Audio cassette (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Conversation with Isaac Bashevis Singer, at Miami Beach1978 Sept 3, (20 mins., in English) Audio cassette (Box 1, Folder 11)